<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Server on Harry Lee&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://harrylee.me/categories/server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Server on Harry Lee&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 16:07:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://harrylee.me/categories/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu: Backup files regularly using expect, rsync and Cron</title>
      <link>https://harrylee.me/blog/2016-05-24-ubuntu-backup-files-regularly-using-rsync-and-cron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harrylee.me/blog/2016-05-24-ubuntu-backup-files-regularly-using-rsync-and-cron/</guid>
      <description>Want to backup your remote files at regular intervals? This post is for you.
This post focuses on: rsync, expect and cron. To access the remote server, I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that you are using ssh (with password authentication) for that. If you use ftp or other protocols, you will have to tweak the instructions a bit. If you are using SSH with public key (well done!), you will have to tweak the rsync command to use public key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu: Suspend and reboot at specific times using Cron</title>
      <link>https://harrylee.me/blog/2015-02-08-ubuntu-suspend-and-reboot-at-specific-times-using-cron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 20:13:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harrylee.me/blog/2015-02-08-ubuntu-suspend-and-reboot-at-specific-times-using-cron/</guid>
      <description>If you have a server at home and you want it to be on only during specific times and not 24&amp;frasl;7, this script is for you.
Cron not only is the best tool for this, it also handles scheduled tasks.
 Cron is a system daemon used to execute desired tasks (in the background) at designated times.
 Method  Install Cron on Ubuntu if it is not already installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu: Sharing externally connected drives over network</title>
      <link>https://harrylee.me/blog/2015-01-10-ubuntu-sharing-externally-connected-drives-over-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 14:29:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harrylee.me/blog/2015-01-10-ubuntu-sharing-externally-connected-drives-over-network/</guid>
      <description>When you have external drives connected to the server, it would be very useful if you can share these drives to users accessing the server as well. This is useful if you have a home media server with externally connected drives.
This post aims to share drives that are NTFS formatted and changing the permissions of the mounted drives.
Method  Unmount the drive that is connected already and remount to another folder giving permissions to users.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>